<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michael&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michael&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Past to Remember</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_past_to_remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_past_to_remember/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know that in years to come I’m going to look back at this post and think, “Wow. I can’t believe I had only &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; started my own blog!” And yes, that is exactly why I’m posting this, to ensure that my future-self has a past to look back to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats of The West - Escaping the Heatwave</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cats_of_the_west_escaping_the_heatwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cats_of_the_west_escaping_the_heatwave/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yet another story from my Reedsy profile. Of course, I’d like to acknowledge Reedsy.com for inspiring this story with their “Set your story during the hottest day of the year” prompt. You can locate them with this link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.reedsy.com/creative-writing-prompts&#34;&gt;https://blog.reedsy.com/creative-writing-prompts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author’s Note: This story is dedicated to my grandparents and their wonderful cast of outside cats: Knight, Farm Cat, Sentinel Cat (my grandma’s favorite), Top Rail Cat, and Mountain Cat (who really does love sitting on the manure pile!) I also want to shout out a quick thank you to my grandpa, who deftly named all five of these cats. Thank you! And to my grandma, who wrote me a detailed list containing the names and descriptions of them, I also want to say thank you—it allowed me to write with ease! Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Girl From the Library</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dear_girl_from_the_library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dear_girl_from_the_library/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s another story inspired by Reedsy prompt, “Write a story in the form of a series of thank you cards.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.reedsy.com/creative-writing-prompts&#34;&gt;https://blog.reedsy.com/creative-writing-prompts&lt;/a&gt;. Without further ado, I present Dear Girl from the Library…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;May 3rd, 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear Girl from the Library&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You might never find this note, and I can only pray that you visit the YA section on a regular basis, but you said you liked romance novels, so I slipped it into one of them. I wanted to thank you, even if we don’t exactly know each other. I lost my dog yesterday morning, which is why I seemed downtrodden, and I was at the library to find a book to escape the misery. Naturally, I went to the YA section to look for some Jeff Wheeler novels—maybe ‘Whispers from Mirrowen’ was finally in stock—and that’s when I ran into you. Funny how a little nudge could get this fantasy guru to try romance, but I’m actually finding myself intrigued by this book. It definitely ebbed my sadness. Thank you for recommending it. So far, chapter fourteen is my favorite!”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/discovery/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This story is actually a spin-off of one of my earlier works. I never finished the original book, but the characters remained rich and well-crafted (particularly Yunru and Shirong), so when I saw this Reedsy Prompt, I felt it was time for them to shine again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You don’t want to return.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prince Yunru halted, feeling the breeze rush in from the Melzkù mountains. It was cool and soothing as it slithered through his hair. “What I want is hardly a concern anymore, Shirong,” he replied. “I wanted my mother and sister, and their souls were taken from me. What matters now is Heftu. What matters now is The Wave, and only the archives can help us.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Courage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dragon_courage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dragon_courage/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taylia’s head bobbed up, down, and side to side in the backseat of the SUV as it left her home in Spearfish. Pax and Kabin hummed softly in their seats, giggling whenever the bumpy road would vibrate their voices. Somehow, they didn’t mind driving to the middle of nowhere and sleeping in a freezing tent. Taylia envied her younger siblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hate the wild,&lt;/em&gt; she thought, mouth pressed into the crook of the window. &lt;em&gt;Why couldn’t we have stayed in a swanky hotel or something?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Preparations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/family_preparations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/family_preparations/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fall is beginning, and I’m sure we’re all excited to break out the pumpkin spice lattes and traditional treats! Join Maylea and Aermis in the zenith of their Autumn as they build a nest for their coming family. And yes, before you ask, I happen to love bluebirds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autumn in Emerwood was beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, there wasn’t any argument that could rival the truth. Emerwood was filled with the rustling of life: the glare of daylight gleaming through the skins of golden and ruby leaves and the trickling sound of flowing brooks. Of course, there weren’t any of those pesky humans to unsettle the peace the woodland had to offer. Otherwise, there would scarcely be any peace at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Mistakes With Christopher Paolini</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fixing_mistakes_with_christopher_paolini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fixing_mistakes_with_christopher_paolini/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve got four rewrites on Book One of The Last Sparkling. Presently, I’m working on Chapter 14’s rewrite, and it’s taking some serious concentration and strength. Right now, I just want to use the old chapter and completely ignore it, maybe even rewrite &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the chapter and use a whole chunk of the old one to compensate for words. Nonetheless, I can’t help but recall a short segment of an interview I watched with Christopher Paolini. He was talking about writers and said that our mistakes (e.g., a bad chapter, a bad sentence, or even a poor word choice) aren’t the deciding factor between good and bad writers. Rather, he said the difference is whether or not you choose to go back and fix your mistakes. I’ve gotta say I agree with him, and here’s why: if we let our writing carelessly drift off without fixing it, we’d never grow in our craft. You wouldn’t ever learn to spot the mistakes BEFORE you’re all the way down the road (or else you’ll get some grueling rewrites like me). I believe the more you repair your mistakes in writing, the less you’ll make those mistakes in the future—or you’ll at least learn to identify them quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Years With ‘Dragons.’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/four_years_with_dragons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/four_years_with_dragons/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 17th this year, one of my old completed books reached its fourth birthday. This was my first original book, which I started when I was fourteen and finished at the beginning of my fifteenth year. I called the story &lt;em&gt;‘Dragons,’&lt;/em&gt; and recently, I rewrote one of its scenes and updated the quality. Today, I want to share it with you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Levi savored the limited time his father gave him and brainstormed a quiet space he could find. The cherry orchard seemed a relatively suitable place, especially after witnessing its peaceful aura the day before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Frozen Valley</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_frozen_valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_frozen_valley/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please enjoy this short scene, starring two characters who are long past during the events of my epic fantasy book. However, there are a few things to keep in mind as you read. One: the fulx are an evil, twisted race of creatures who feast on fear and have a habit of feezing dragons. Two: ‘sparkling’ is the technical term for a dragon rider, who, when bonded with a dragon, can overpower the fulx. Sparklings control a magical fire, whereas fulx control a magical ice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Sparkling (Trilogy Blurb)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_last_sparkling_trilogy_blurb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 21:08:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the_last_sparkling_trilogy_blurb/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a ‘trilogy blurb’ for all The Last Sparkling books. Each one will have its own plot, but overall, this covers all three (well, hopefully three—I haven’t worked everything out that far.). Currently, I am about 85% through the first draft of Bonded, book one of The Last Sparkling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long ago, seven extraordinary thieves obtained the power of the Iyishhräll in an attempt to pilfer its magic. As a result, they became bonded with the children of the dragon monarchs. For this heinous crime, they were thus despised by the dragons. But when a mysterious evil threatens, the dragons realize that they need these seven humans. Filled with a new passion for protecting the dragon race, the former thieves opposed this evil, riding through the skies upon their bonded dragons. The great war cost them everything: blood, anguish, and in the end, their lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
